A Calendar of The Jefferson Papers of the University of Virginia
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Series I: Dated Materials
  - JOHN HENDERSON. PROPERTY SCHEDULE., 1806 December 25.; D. 1 pp. Attested by John Nicholas, Clerk. Endorsed by T. J. McGregor Library, #564.
    Schedule of the property of John Henderson, deeds, and papers in trust for purpose of securing certain moneys to James Lewis and Matthew Henderson.
    [977]
  - WILLIAM ROSCOE to THOMAS JEFFERSON., 1806.; ALS. 2 pp. File draft. Photostat. Original owned by City of Liverpool Public Library. #5128-a.
    Sends Life and Pontificate of Leo X, by way of Ra[lph?] Eddens of Philadelphia.
    [2725]
  - EDMUND BACON, Monticello, to THOMAS JEFFERSON., 1807 January 1.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    Nail rod. Books from Richmond by Mr. Johnson. Gardening and brickmaking as Mr. Chisolm directed. Hogs and sheep.
    [2727]
  - JOHN PERRY to THOMAS JEFFERSON., 1807 January 6.; ADS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Carr-Cary Papers, #1231.
    Order on T. J. in favor of Dabney Carr.
    [979]
  - JOHN BARNES, Georgetown, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Washington., 1807 January 13.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    State of T. J.'s finances for the ensuing months.
    [980]
  - DABNEY CARR, Charlottesville, to THOMAS JEFFERSON., 1807 January 16.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Carr-Cary Papers, #1231.
    Enclosing a draft on T. J. by John Perry, which pays Mrs. Carter for hire of slaves. Martha Carr mentioned.
    [981]
  - WILSON CARY NICHOLAS to THOMAS JEFFERSON., [1807 January 20].; ALS. 5 pp. Fragment. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397. Printed: B of R VIII 427 (MS. in DLC).
    Urges that T. J. run for another term. Notes accomplishments of T. J.'s administration. Incompetency of Henry Dearborn as Secretary of War. Suggests Dearborn be made Collector of Boston. Burr Conspiracy. Defenselessness of New Orleans. References to James Wilkinson.
    [982]
  - JOHN DICKINSON, Wilmington, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Washington., 1807 January 22.; ALS. 5 pp. Endorsed by T. J. McGregor Library, #564.
    Recommends civil reforms and legislative action to prevent lawsuits and protect the citizen; policy on territories. Country loves Jefferson despite hatred of Federalists.
    [983]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Washington, to DABNEY CARR., 1807 January 26.; ALS. 1 pp. File draft. Endorsed by T. J. Carr-Cary Papers, #1231.
    Payment of John Perry's draft on T. J.
    [984]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Washington, to CRAVEN PEYTON., 1807 January 28.; ALS. 1 pp. File draft. Endorsed by T. J. McGregor Library, #564.
    Wants William Wirt to assist George Hay in suit against John Henderson.
    [985]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON to CAESAR A. RODNEY., 1807 February 5.; AL. 1 pp. Photostat. Location of original not known. #3449.
    Yrujo suit against William Duane, editor of the Aurora.
    [2728]
  - DABNEY CARR, Charlottesville, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Washington., 1807 February 6.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Carr-Cary Papers, #1231.
    Encloses draft from John Perry, payable in monthly installments.
    [986]
  - WILLIAM A. BURWELL to THOMAS JEFFERSON., 1807 February 18.; ALS. 1 pp. Owned by the Misses Margaret and Olivia Taylor. #8937.
    Dispute between Thomas Mann Randolph, Jr. and T. J.
    [2728-a]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Washington, to THOMAS MANN RANDOLPH, JR., Edgehill., 1807 February 19.; ALS. 1 pp. File draft. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Declaring his affection and respect. Assurances that he does not think Thomas Mann Randolph has joined the Federalists. References to Colonel Heath.
    [987]
  - WILLIAM A. BURWELL to THOMAS JEFFERSON., 1807 February 20.; ALS. 1 pp. Owned by the Misses Margaret and Olivia Taylor. #8937.
    [2728-b]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, COMMISSION OF JOHN MONTRESOR HASWELL, U.S. NAVY., 1807 February 26; DS. 1 pp. #7379. Clifton Waller Barrett Library.
    Signed by T. J.
  - WILLIAM A. BURWELL to THOMAS JEFFERSON., 1807 February 28.; ALS. 1 pp. #8937.
    Health and state of mind of Thomas Mann Randolph, Jr. Joseph brings carriage.
    [2728-c]
  - W. A. BURWELL to THOMAS JEFFERSON., [1807] March 3.; ALS. 1 pp. #8937.
    Thomas Mann Randolph, Jr.'s regrets for having left T. J. and Randolph's state of mind.
    [2728-d]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Washington, to MARTHA JEFFERSON RANDOLPH., 1807 March 12.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #10362.
    T. J. writes to his daughter regarding the illness of her husband, Thomas Mann Randolph, Jr.
  - MARTHA JEFFERSON RANDOLPH, Edgehill, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Washington., 1807 March 14.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Thomas Mann Randolph's illness. Arrival of Mr. Burwell.
    [988]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON Washington, to JOSEPH CARRINGTON CABELL., 1807 March 18.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #201.
    Appreciates receipt of [James] Workman's pamphlet; disapproves his use of office as judge to liberate accomplices. Fault in our Constitution in irresponsible power of the judiciary.
    [989]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON to MARTHA JEFFERSON RANDOLPH., 1807 March 20.; ALS. 1 pp. Draft copy. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    T. J.'s headache. Health of Mr. Randolph, Lemaire, and Mr. Freeman.
    [2729]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Washington, to JOHN WAYLES EPPES., 1807 March 21.; ALS. 1 pp. #38-576.
    Suggests sending mare to Eppes, so as not to endanger her foal. Thomas Mann Randolph, Jr. s illness. T. J. s headache.
    [990]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Washington, to CAESAR A. RODNEY., 1807 March 30.; ALS. 1 pp. Photostat. Location of original not known. #3449.
    Lost paper found. To Monticello.
    [2730]
  - RANDOLPH LEWIS, Byrd, Va., to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Washington., 1807 April 20.; ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Offering to sell his slave who is the wife of T. J.'s Moses, since Lewis is moving to Kentucky.
    [991]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello, to JOHN CARR., 1807 April 28.; ALS. 2 pp. File draft. Endorsed by T. J. Carr-Cary Papers, #1231.
    Recommends course of study for Carr's son, Lewis Carr, preparatory to entrance at William and Mary.
    [992]
  - EDMUND BACON, Monticello, to THOMAS JEFFERSON., 1807 May 22.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    Work at mill. Mr. Perry works on scow and Mr. Maddox on toll mill. Thorn hedges.
    [2731]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Washington, to DABNEY CARR., 1807 May 25.; ALS. 1 pp. File draft. Endorsed by T. J. Carr-Cary Papers, #1231.
    Delays payment of John Perry's draft in favor of Carr because of heavy bills for wine. Remittance to James Walker as bail for Stewart in return for year's hire of Melinda (slave?).
    [993]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Washington, to JOHN WAYLES EPPES, Eppington., 1807 May 28.; ALS. 1 pp. #38-576. Printed: Ford IX 67-68; B of R VI 142 (MS. in DLC).
    Health of Francis Eppes II. John Wayles Eppes' mare in good traveling order. Friendly letter from Bey of Tunis. Despite high opinion of Marshall's integrity, finds jury in Aaron Burr's trial unfairly weighted with two Federalists, four Quids, and ten Republicans. Mentions Eppes' slave, Martin.
    [994]
  - DABNEY CARR, Charlottesville, to THOMAS JEFFERSON., 1807 May 29.; ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    Perry's bond. Baltimore creditors of John Speer, assignee, demand Maddox's draft to E. Alexander which was presented at Monticello. Judgment against Stewart and Walker. Mentions Melinda and Samuel Carr.
    [2732]
  - EDMUND BACON to THOMAS JEFFERSON., 1807 June 6.; ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    Flood damage to toll mill. Mr. Perry doing scow roof. Hedges. Purchase of sheep. Mr. Carr's and Mr. Craven's mules. Mentions Mr. Walker.
    [2734]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Washington, to JOHN BARNES., 1807 June 6.; ALS. 1 pp. Owned by Thomas Jefferson Memorial Foundation. #7443-e.
    Encloses check on the Bank of the U.S. Debt to Barnes. Barnes to collect Beckley's debt and credit T. J.
    [2734-a]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON PATENT to WILLIAM PHOEBUS., 1807 June 9.; DS. 2 pp. #2626. Photostat. Original owned by John D. Murphy.
    Countersigned by James Madison. For a salivating device. Description of device by Phoebus.
    [995]
  - EDMUND BACON TO THOMAS JEFFERSON., 1807 June 12.; ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    Mill and canal flooding. Mentions Davy.
    [2735]
  - JAMES TUCKER, Norfolk, to THOMAS JEFFERSON., 1807 June 27.; L. 1 pp. Typescript copy from Norfolk Gazette and Publick Ledger. Location of original not known. #3439.
    Resolution of officers sailing to and from ports of Norfolk and Portsmouth.
    [2736]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON LAND GRANT to EDWARD S. HALL, Baltimore County, Md., 1807 July 1.; DS. 1 pp. Seal. James Manuscripts, #38-402.
    Patent for lot in Range Eight, Section Three of the Northwest Territory. Countersigned by James Madison.
    [996]
  - EDMUND BACON, Monticello, to THOMAS JEFFERSON., 1807 July 3.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    Monticello barn. Horse mended. Mentions Mr. Perry and James Clark.
    [2737]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Washington, to MASTERS AND OFFICERS SAILING TO AND FROM PORTS OF NORFOLK AND PORTSMOUTH., 1807 July 8.; L. 1 pp. Typescript copy from Norfolk Gazette and Publick Ledger. Location of original not known. #3439. Printed: L and B XI, 261.
    Defense of Fort Norfolk, Craney Island, Elizabeth and James Rivers.
    [2738]
  - RANDOLPH JEFFERSON, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1807 July 9.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Carr-Cary Papers, #1231. Printed: Mayo 13.
    Terms for sale of clover and grass seed. Reference to Thomas Mann Randolph, Jr.
    [997]
  - MARTHA JEFFERSON RANDOLPH, Edgehill, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Washington., 1807 July 11.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #38-755.
    Request for a comb. Heel of shoe needs changing. News of Chesapeake affair. Fresh meat supply for the summer. Mentions Edmund Bacon.
    [998]
  - JOHN DICKINSON, Wilmington, to CAESAR A. RODNEY, Washington., 1807 July 22.; ALS. 3 pp. Endorsed by T. J. McGregor Library, #564.
    Interdiction of British ships-of-war should be strictly enforced. Hopes T. J. will accept another term; approval of T. J.'s late proclamation and of his defeat of the Burr Conspiracy.
    [999]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON to CAESAR A. RODNEY., 1807 July 26.; AN. 1 pp. #3449. Photostat. Location of original not known. #3449.
    Robert Bowie and Mr. Wilkinson invited to dine.
    [2739]
  - JOHN BORROWS to THOMAS JEFFERSON., 1807 August 1.; ADS. 1 pp. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    #5533.
    [2740]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON to JOHN BOYER., 1807 August 3.; DS. 1 pp. Oak Hill Papers. #3248.
    Ensign's commission. Countersigned by James Madisom.
    [2741]
  - JOHN BARNES, Georgetown, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, [Monticello]., 1807 August 6.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Payments to William Pennock of Norfolk and to Jones & Howell of Philadelphia.
    [1000]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON to ANNE LOUIS DE TOUSARD., 1807 August 7.; ANS. 1 pp. #4195.
    Subscribes to Louis De Tousard's American Artillerist's Companion.
    [2742]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello, to CRAVEN PEYTON., 1807 August 10.; ALS. 1 pp. File draft. Endorsed by T. J. McGregor Library, #564.
    Cannot undertake the settlement between Col. [Nicholas?] Lewis and Peyton because of unusual press of public affairs brought on by Chesapeake affair.
    [1001]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello, to WILLIAM H. CABELL., 1807 August 11.; ALS. 5 pp. Paul Mellon Bequest. #11621. Printed: L and B XI, 318-23.
    T. J. responds to Cabell's request for an opinion on a Congressional act for accepting the service of volunteers in the armed services.
    [2742-a]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello, to RANDOLPH JEFFERSON., 1807 August 12.; ALS. 1 pp. File draft. Endorsed by T. J. Carr-Cary Papers, #1231. Printed: Mayo 14.
    Payment for clover and greensward seed. Clover to he sent to Burgess Griffin at Poplar Forest. Mentions Mr. Crouch, Mr. Brown, and Anna Scott Marks.
    [1002]
  - JOHN BARNES, Georgetown, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1807 August 19.; ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Enclosure: D. 2 pp. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    James Davidson's explanation of enclosed bill of exchange. Damage from storms near Monticello. Offers draft or a remittance. Enclosure: bill of exchange drawn by Stephen Cathalan, Jr., on T. J. in favor of Capt. William Hazard.
    [1003]
  - JOHN BARNES, Georgetown, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1807 September 3.; ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Financial matters. T. J.'s fatiguing visit to Bedford County. Order on Jonathan Smith, of the Bank of Pennsylvania, for Tadeusz Kosciuszko's account.
    [1004]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello, to WILLIAM H. CABELL., 1807 September 18.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. McGregor Library, #453. Printed: L & B XI 369-370; B of R VI 61 (MS. in DLC).
    To the Governor of Virginia, concerning Lowrie's correspondence. Approves Cabell's instructions to Major Newton. Provisions for troops. Report from Mr. Belscher of Gloucester regarding contraventions of the proclamation denying British vessels the hospitality of American waters.
    [1005]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello, to CAESAR A. RODNEY, Wilmington, Del., 1807 September 18.; AN. 1 pp. Photostat. Original owned by Victor B. Levit. #8265-b.
    Unidentified legal matter.
    [2742-b]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON to JOHN BARNES., 1807 September 23.; ADS. 1 pp. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    Promissory note on bank of Columbia.
    [2742-c]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello, to JOHN WAYLES EPPES., 1807 September 26.; ALS. 1 pp. #38-576. Printed: B of R VI 143 (MS. in DLC).
    Purchase of horse. Shipment of harpsichord, table, copying press, and a bust to Mr. George Jefferson at Richmond. Asks instructions about presses. Acquisition of Floridas and peace with England very uncertain. Mentions Mr. Coles. Francis Eppes II, and Mr. and Mrs. Francis Eppes I.
    [1006]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON Monticello, to JAMES MADISON., 1807 September 26.; L. 1 pp. #251. Typescript copy. Original owned by Samuel H. McVitty.
    Plans for meeting Madison at Montpellier. Mentions Dolly Madison.
    [1007]
  - EDMUND BACON ACCOUNT., 1807 September; AD. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    Payments to James Carr, Thomas Burress, Jacob Kooper, John Peyton, Richard Anderson, John Rogers, James Butler.
    [2743]
  - W. MARKEY. BILL TO ETIENNE LEMAIRE FOR THOMAS JEFFERSON., 1807 October 2.; ADS. 1 pp. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
  - BENJAMIN JONES. BILL TO ETIENNE LEMAIRE FOR THOMAS JEFFERSON., 1807 October 3.; ADS. 1 pp. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
  - FRANCIS CLARK. BILL TO ETIENNE LEMAIRE FOR THOMAS JEFFERSON., 1807 October 2.; ADS. 1 pp. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
  - CRAVEN PEYTON, Stump Island, to THOMAS JEFFERSON., 1807 October 16.; ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. McGregor Library, #564.
    Offers to sell Colle to T. J. and to trade other tracts with Mr. Carr. T. J.'s tenant at Milton, [Richard?] Johnson, has corn and wheat which Edmund Bacon should call for. Warehouse money all drawn. Firewood cutting prohibited at Milton.
    [1009]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Washington, to JOHN BARNES., 1807 October 21.; DS. 1 pp. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    Note payable at Bank of Columbia.
    [2744]
  - EDMUND BACON, Monticello, to T. J. AL., 1807 October 24.; Fragment. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    Accounts of Mr. Peyton and cooper. Mr. Craven's tobacco. Timothy planting. Corn. Work on dam. [Break in text]. Property sale. Mentions Mr. Shoemaker, Mr. Perry.
    [2745]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Washington, to CRAVEN PEYTON., 1807 October 25.; ALS. 1 pp. File draft. Endorsed by T. J. McGregor Library, #564.
    Debts will not permit him to buy Colle. Instructions regarding corn and wheat to be delivered to Edmund Bacon. Purchase of the right of James Lewis and Matthew Henderson in the Bennett Henderson estate. Joseph C. Cabell might buy Peyton's land.
    [1010]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON SHIP'S PAPERS., 1807 November 5.; DS. 1 pp. #1882. Photostat.
    Clearance papers for Brig Alexander, William Miller Captain, bound for Guadeloupe. Countersigned by James Madison.
    [1011]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Washington, to JOHN MINOR., 1807 November 7.; ALS. 1 pp. Photostat. Original owned by Mrs. James H. Johnson. #8917.
    Mrs. Dangerfield's slaves. Disagreement with England. Amendment of the Constitution for removal of judges, and Senate proposal for appointment of judges. Mentions L. W. Dangerfield and Sarah Dangerfield.
    [2745-a]
  - EDMUND BACON, Monticello, to THOMAS JEFFERSON., 1807 November 8.; ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    Davy to Washington. Corn from Mr. Craven, Robert Teril, Robert Burress, Mr. Peyton. Stewart drunk and working poorly. Garden work. No work at cooper's shop, Belt's home, or head gate. Mr. Maddox broke arm.
    [2746]
  - CRAVEN PEYTON to WILLIAM C. BRADBOURN, Jacob Cooper, William D. Fitch, David Higginbotham, C. T. Wertenbaker, Richard Johnson, Thomas Wells, Paul Weyate, David Anderson, Mary Thorp, Reuben Grady, and John Burks., 1807 November 11.; ADS. 2 pp. McGregor Library, #564.
    Terms for cutting firewood on Jefferson's land near Milton.
    [1012]
  - EDMUND BACON, Monticello, to THOMAS JEFFERSON., 1807 November 15.; AL. Fragment. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    Money to be sent by Mr. Craven.
    [2747]
  - JOHN HENDERSON. DEED to CRAVEN PEYTON., 1807 November 17.; DS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. McGregor Library, #564.
    Conveying shares of Frances L., Lucy L., and Nancy Henderson in the estate of their father, Bennett Henderson, signed by John Henderson as guardian. Witnesses: Fleming Turner, M[artin] Dawson, James Bullock. Receipt from Henderson for money paid by Peyton on the above. Witness: Fleming Turner.
    [1013]
  - LUCY LEWIS, Monteagle, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Washington., 1807 November 19.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Letter of farewell upon leaving for mouth of Cumberland River. Mr. Peyton's goodness to her.
    [1014]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Washington, to JAMES DINSMORE, Monticello., 1807 November 25.; ALS. 1 pp. Photostat. Original owned by W. Bedford Moore. #9487.
    Davy bringing box of articles furnished by Dr. Ott. Lead has left Philadelphia. Has sent Mr. Bacon books and other packages for Monticello to be stored in greenhouse.
    [2747-a]
  - EDMUND BACON, Monticello, to THOMAS JEFFERSON., 1807 December 11.; AL. Fragment. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    Mrs. Dangerfield's runaway slaves. Mr. Belt wants new bolting cloth. Davy, not Mr. Perry, can make addition to the nursery. Mr. Grady's money.
    [2748]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Washington, to JOHN BARNES., 1807 December 16.; DS. 1 pp. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    [2749]
  - EDMUND BACON, Monticello, to THOMAS JEFFERSON., 1807 December 18.; AL. Fragment. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    Runaway slaves not at Mrs. Dangerfield's. Wants T. J. to prevent his being made a soldier.
    [2750]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Washington, to ELIZABETH HOUSE TRIST., 1807 December 22.; ALS. 1 pp. Photostat. #5213-d.
  - EDMUND BACON, Monticello, to THOMAS JEFFERSON., 1807 December 25.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    Mrs. Lewis' account for turkeys, bacon, oats, and vegetables gotten by Edmund Bacon, Mr. Freeman, and Mr. Lilly. Hogs. Thomas Mann Randolph, Jr. took two wagon horses.
    [2751]
  - MARTHA JEFFERSON RANDOLPH, Edgehill, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Washington., 1808 January 2.; ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    T. J.'s health. David and William Randolph in bankruptcy. Thomas Mann Randolph's responsibilities.
    [1015]
  - ROSWELL SALTONSTALL, New York, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Washington., 1808 January 2.; ALS. 3 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #2564. Printed: Ford-Bixby 155-156.
    Letter from a loyal but crackpot Republican. Advises annexation of the Floridas, but Canada and Nova Scotia "a dred to our union" if taken. Evils of the Quakers and Methodists in attacks on T. J. Mentions General Lyman, James Madison, William Thornton, William B. Giles, and [John] Pope.
    [1016]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Washington, to BENJAMIN RUSH, Philadelphia., 1808 January 3.; ALS. 1 pp. #1947. Photostat. Original owned by Dr. Josiah C. Treat. Printed: L & B XI 412-413; B of R VI 399 (MS. in DLC).
    Appointment of Benjamin Waterhouse, who introduced vaccination in this country, to the Marine Hospital of Boston. T. J. Randolph's prospective trip to Philadelphia. Mr. Rose's mission. Embargo.
    [1017]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON to JOHN TAYLOR., 1808 January 6; L. 1 pp. Typed transcript of extract contained in: 1808 January 25, John Taylor, Caroline, to Thomas C. Martin. #3200. Location of originals unknown.
    T. J. asks Taylor to contact Martin and ask him to make a drill, which T. J. will send to the agricultural society of Paris.
  - EDMUND BACON, Monticello, to THOMAS JEFFERSON., 1808 January 8.; AL. Fragment. 1 pp. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    Owes John Carr. Peter Minor buys nails from penitentiary. [Break in text]. Runaway slaves.
    [2752]
  - EDMUND BACON, Monticello, to THOMAS JEFFERSON., 1808 January 15.; AL. Fragment. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    Mr. Belt keeping his horse at the mill. Bigtail sheep flock increasing.
    [2753]
  - ANNE CARY RANDOLPH, Edgehill, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Washington., 1808 January 22.; ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Ellen's and her own education. Flowers, trees, and vines at Edgehill: cypress vine, prickly ash trees, mignonette, marigold. Lucy Lewis has gone to Kentucky. References to Virginia and Mary Randolph, Mrs. [Nicholas?] Lewis, and Aunt Jane [Randolph].
    [1018]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON to SENATE OF U.S., 1808 January 30.; ALS. 1 pp. Photostat. Location of original unknown. #3449.
    Treaties with Ottowas, Chippewas, Wyandots, and Potawatomis. made at Detroit, and with Choctaws at Pooshapukanuck.
    [2754]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Washington, to MR. DEBLOIS, Alexandria., 1808 February 19.; ANS. 1 pp. #4574.
    Goods to Gibson & Jefferson, Richmond, by Capt. Johnson.
    [2755]
  - ANNE CARY RANDOLPH, Edgehill, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Washington., 1808 February 19.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Peas, roses, and amaryllis in her gardens. Reported engagement of Evalina Bolling to Mr. Garett (Alexander Garrett?) of Charlottesville.
    [1020]
  - MARTHA JEFFERSON RANDOLPH, Edgehill, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Washington., 1808 February 20.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Introducing Beverley Randolph, who is living in young Nourse's place. Broken seal and watch key. Mentions Dolly Madison.
    [1021]
  - EDMUND BACON, Monticello, to THOMAS JEFFERSON., 1808 February 26.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    Stewart's account. Dinsmore levels land. Corn from Mr. Mullins. Needs nail rod, as George Jefferson has none at Richmond. Mentions Mr. Walker, Thomas Mann Randolph, Jr.
    [2756]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, wrapper for accounts and vouchers, 1808 [February?]; AD, 1 pp. #13478..
    A small slip of paper, with ends sealed together by wax to form a circular wrapper. On the outside T. J. has written "Daugherty Joseph Acct. & Vouchers. 1808."
  - EDMUND BACON to THOMAS JEFFERSON., 1808 March 4.; ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    Thorn hedges. Sowing oats in field bought from Mr. Craven. Corn planting. Small ewe that had been at Alexander's died. Joe wants tin for coopers.
    [2757]